I'll find you later.
我一会儿去找你。
It's not safe.
不安全。
Let me send some men with you.
让我派人跟你去。
I'm going alone.
我一个人去。
In the name of the one true queen,
Daenerys Targaryen,
以唯一真正的女王之名，
I sentence you to die.
我判你死刑。
Jon: Grey worm!
乔恩：灰虫子！
It's over.
这是结束了。
These men are prisoners.
这些人是囚犯。
It is not over until
the queen's enemies are defeated.
它不会结束，直到
女王的敌人被打败了。
How much more defeated
do you want them to be?
多挫败
你希望他们是吗？
- They're on their knees.
- They are breathing.
-他们跪在地上。
-他们在呼吸。
Look around you, friend. We won.
看看你的周围，朋友。我们赢了。
I obey my queen's commands,
not yours.
我服从女王的命令
不是你的。
Jon: And what
are the queen's commands?
乔恩：那是什么？
是女王的命令吗？
"Kill all who follow
Cersei Lannister."
“杀了所有跟随的人
兰尼斯特瑟曦。”
These are free men.
他们是自由人。
They chose to fight for her.
他们选择为她而战。
Davos: Easy, men. Easy! Easy.
戴佛斯：淡定，伙计们。简单!容易实现。
Jon.
乔恩。
We should speak with the queen.
我们应该和王后谈谈。
Blood of my blood.
我的血。
You kept all your promises to me.
你遵守了所有对我的承诺。
You killed my enemies
in their iron suits.
你杀死了我的敌人
穿着他们的铁甲。
You tore down their stone houses.
你们拆毁了他们的石屋。
You gave me the seven kingdoms!
你给了我七个王国！
Torgo nudho.
Torgo nudho。
You have walked beside me
since the Plaza of pride.
你一直陪在我身边
自从骄傲广场以来
You are the bravest of men,
the most loyal of soldiers.
你是最勇敢的人，
最忠诚的士兵。
I name you commander
of all my forces,
我任命你为指挥官
在我所有的力量中，
the queen's master of war.
女王的战争大师。
Unsumed.
它。
All of you were torn from your
mothers' arms and raised as slaves.
你们都被从你们的
在母亲的臂弯里，像奴隶一样长大。
Now...
现在…
You are liberators!
你们是解放者！
You have freed the people of king's
landing from the grip of a tyrant!
你解放了国王学院的人民
摆脱暴君的控制！
But the war is not over.
但是战争还没有结束。
We will not lay down our Spears
until we have liberated
我们不会放下我们的长矛
直到我们解放
all the people of the world!
世界上所有的人！
From winterfell to dorne,
从临冬城到多恩，
from lannisport to qarth,
从兰尼斯港到魁尔斯，
from the summer isles to the Jade sea!
从夏天的小岛到翡翠海！
Women, men and children
女人，男人和孩子
have suffered too long
beneath the wheel.
受了太久的苦
在车轮下。
Will you break the wheel with me?
你愿意和我一起摔车轮吗？
You freed your brother.
你释放了你的兄弟。
You committed treason.
你犯了叛国罪。
I freed my brother.
我释放了我的兄弟。
And you slaughtered a city.
你屠杀了一座城市。
Take him.
带他。
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Hey, what happened?
嘿，怎么了？
I came to kill Cersei.
我是来杀瑟曦的。
Your queen got there first.
你的女王先到的。
Jon: She's everyone's queen now.
乔恩：她现在是每个人的女王。
Try telling sansa.
试着告诉珊莎。
Wait for me outside the city gates.
I'll come find you.
在城门外等我。
我会去找你的。
Jon.
乔恩。
She knows who you are.
她知道你是谁。
Who you really are.
你到底是谁。
You'll always be a threat to her.
你永远都是她的威胁。
And I know a killer when I see one.
我一眼就能认出凶手。
Did you bring any wine?
你带酒了吗？
Well...
嗯…
Thank you for coming to see me.
谢谢你来看我。
Our queen doesn't keep prisoners
for long.
我们的女王不囚禁囚犯
太久。
I suppose there's
a crude kind of justice.
我想有
一种粗糙的正义。
I betrayed my closest friend
and watched him burn.
我背叛了我最亲密的朋友
看着他燃烧。
Now varys's ashes can tell my ashes:
现在瓦里斯的骨灰可以告诉我：
"See, I told you."
“看，我告诉过你。”
It just occurred to me.
我刚想起来。
I'm talking to the only man alive
who knows where I'm going.
我在和唯一活着的人说话
谁知道我要去哪里。
So is there life after death?
那么死后还有生命吗？
Not that I've seen.
我没见过。
I should be thankful.
我应该心存感激。
Oblivion is the best
I could hope for.
遗忘是最好的
我所希望的。
I strangled my lover.
我勒死了我的爱人。
I shot my own father with a crossbow.
I betrayed my queen.
我用弓弩射死了自己的父亲。
我背叛了王后。
- You didn't.
- I did.
-你没有。
-是的。
And I'd do it again,
now that I've seen what I've seen.
我还会再来一次
现在我看到了我看到的。
I chose my fate.
我选择了我的命运。
The people of king's landing did not.
君临的人民却没有。
I can'tjustify what happened.
我无法为所发生的事情辩护。
I won't try.
我不会尝试的。
- But the war is over now.
- Is it?
-但战争已经结束了。
-是吗？
When you heard her
talking to her soldiers,
当你听到她的声音
对她的士兵说，
did she sound like someone
who's done fighting?
她听起来像什么人吗
谁打完仗了？
She liberated the people
of slaver's bay.
她解放了人民
奴隶湾。
She liberated the people
of king's landing.
她解放了人民
君临的。
And she'll go on liberating
她会继续解放
until the people of the world
are free...
直到世人皆知
是免费的…
And she rules them all.
她统治着他们。
And you've been by her side,
counseling her.
你一直在她身边
咨询她。
Until today.
直到今天。
Varys was right.
瓦里斯说得对。
I was wrong.
我错了。
It was vanity
to think I could guide her.
这是虚荣
以为我能引导她
Our queen's nature is fire and blood.
我们女王的本性是火与血。
You think our house words
are stamped on our bodies
你想想我们家的话
烙印在我们身上
when we're born
and that's who we are?
当我们出生的时候
这就是我们？
Ah, then I'd be fire and blood too.
那我也会是血与火。
She's not her father,
no more than you're tywin Lannister.
她不是她父亲，
就像你是泰温·兰尼斯特一样。
My father was an evil man.
My sister was an evil woman.
我父亲是个邪恶的人。
我妹妹是个邪恶的女人。
Pile up all the bodies
of all the people they ever killed,
把尸体都堆起来
他们杀了那么多人，
there still won't be half as many
as our beautiful queen slaughtered
仍然不会有一半的人
当我们美丽的女王被屠杀时
in a single day.
在一天之内。
Cersei left her no choice.
瑟曦让她别无选择。
The moment the gates fell,
the battle was over.
大门倒下的那一刻，
战斗结束了。
She saw her friend beheaded.
她看到她的朋友被砍头。
She saw her dragon
shot out of the sky.
她看到了她的龙
从天空中射出。
And she burned down a city for it.
她为此烧毁了一座城市。
Ah, it's easy to judge when you're
standing far from the battlefield.
啊，当你
远离战场。
Would you have done it?
你会这么做吗？
What?
怎么啦？
You've been up there,
on a dragon's back.
你去过那里，
骑在龙背上。
You've had that power.
Would you have burned the city down?
你有这种能力。
你会把城市烧了吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Yes, you do.
是的，你有。
You won't say because
you don't want to betray her...
你不会说因为
你不想背叛她…
But you know.
但是你知道。
What's it matter what I'd do?
我做什么有什么关系？
It matters more than anything.
这比什么都重要。
When she murdered
the slavers of astapor,
当她谋杀
阿斯塔波的奴隶贩子，
I'm sure no one
but the slavers complained.
我肯定没人
但是奴隶贩子们抱怨起来。
After all, they were evil men.
毕竟，他们是坏人。
When she crucified hundreds of
meereenese nobles, who could argue?
当她将数百人钉死在十字架上
弥林贵族们，谁能反驳呢？
They were evil men.
他们是邪恶的人。
The Dothraki khals she burned alive?
被她活活烧死的多斯拉克卡奥？
They would have done worse to her.
他们会对她做更糟的事。
Everywhere she goes, evil men die
她所到之处，恶人必死无疑
and we cheer her for it.
我们为她加油。
And she grows more powerful
她变得越来越强大
and more sure
that she is good and right.
更确定的是
她是善良和正确的。
She believes her destiny is
to build a better world for everyone.
她相信她的命运是
为每个人建立一个更美好的世界。
If you believed that...
如果你相信……
If you truly believed it,
如果你真的相信
wouldn't you kill whoever stood
between you and paradise?
你不会杀了站着的人吗
在你和天堂之间？
I know you love her.
我知道你爱她。
I love her too.
我也爱她。
Not as successfully as you.
没有你成功。
But I believed in her
with all my heart.
但我相信她
全心全意。
Love is more powerful than reason.
爱比理智更有力量。
We all know that.
我们都知道这一点。
Look at my brother.
看看我弟弟。
"Love is the death of duty."
“爱是责任的死亡。”
You just came up with that?
你就这么想出来的？
Maesteraemon said it
a long time ago.
师傅说的
很久以前的事了。
Sometimes duty is the death of love.
有时责任是爱情的死亡。
You are the shield
that guards the realms of men.
你是我的盾牌
守护着人类的王国。
You've always tried
to do the right thing.
你一直在努力
做正确的事。
No matter the cost,
无论代价如何，
you've tried to protect people.
你试图保护人们。
Who is the greatest threat
to the people now?
谁是最大的威胁
现在轮到人民了吗？
It's a terrible thing I'm asking.
这是一件很糟糕的事情。
It's also the right thing.
这也是正确的事情。
Do you think I'm the last man
she'll execute?
你以为我是最后一个男人吗
她会执行吗?
Who is more dangerous than
the rightful heir to the iron throne?
谁比他更危险
铁王座的合法继承人？
That's her decision.
She is the queen.
这是她的决定。
她是女王。
I'm sorry it came to this.
很抱歉事情发展到这个地步。
And your sisters?
你的姐妹们呢？
Do you see them bending the knee?
你看到他们屈膝了吗？
My sisters will be loyal
to the throne.
我的姐妹们会很忠诚
为了王位。
Why do you think sansa
told me the truth about you?
珊莎，你觉得为什么
告诉我关于你的真相？
Because she doesn't want dany
to be queen.
因为她不想要丹妮
成为女王。
- She doesn't get to choose.
- No.
-她没资格选择
——没有。
But you do.
但你知道。
And you have to choose now.
你现在必须做出选择。
When I was a girl,
my brother told me it was made
当我还是个女孩的时候，
我哥哥告诉我这是真的
with 1,000 swords
from aegon's fallen enemies.
带着一千把剑
来自伊耿死去的敌人。
What do 1,000 swords look like
1000把剑长什么样
in the mind of a little girl
who can't count to 20?
在一个小女孩的心中
谁不会数到20？
I imagined a mountain of swords
too high to climb.
我想象出一座剑山
太高了，爬不上去。
So many fallen enemies,
那么多倒下的敌人，
you could only see
the soles of aegon's feet.
你只能看到
伊耿的脚底。
Jon: I saw them executing
Lannister prisoners in the street.
乔恩：我看到他们被处决了
兰尼斯特家的囚犯在街上。
They said they were acting
on your orders.
他们说他们在演戏
听你的命令。
- It was necessary.
- Necessary?
-这是必要的。
——有必要吗?
Have you been down there?
你去过那里吗？
Have you seen?
你看到了吗？
Children, little children, burned!
孩子们，孩子们，被烧死了！
I tried to make peace with Cersei.
我试着和瑟曦讲和。
She used their innocence
as a weapon against me.
她利用了他们的天真
作为对付我的武器。
- She thought it would cripple me.
- And Tyrion?
-她觉得这会让我残废
-提利昂呢？
He conspired behind my back
with my enemies.
他背着我搞阴谋
和我的敌人。
How have you treated people
who've done the same to you,
你是怎样对待别人的
对你做过同样的事
even when it broke your heart?
即使它伤了你的心？
Forgive him.
原谅他。
- I can't.
- You can.
-不行。
-你可以的。
You can forgive all of them,
make them see they made a mistake.
你可以原谅他们所有人
让他们知道他们犯了一个错误。
Make them understand.
让他们理解。
Please, dany.
请丹妮。
We can't hide behind small mercies.
我们不能躲在小小的仁慈后面。
The world we need
我们需要的世界
won't be built by men
loyal to the world we have.
不会由人类建造
忠于我们所拥有的世界。
The world we need
is a world of mercy. It has to be.
我们需要的世界
是一个充满怜悯的世界。它必须是。
And it will be.
它将会是。
It's not easy to see something
that's never been before.
看东西不容易
这是前所未有的。
A good world.
一个美好的世界。
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
How do you know it'll be good?
你怎么知道它会好？
Because I know what is good.
因为我知道什么是好的。
And so do you.
你也一样。
- I don't.
- You do.
-我不知道。
-你有。
You do. You've always known.
你做的事情。你一直都知道。
What about everyone else?
其他人呢？
All the other people
who think they know what's good.
所有其他人
他们认为自己知道什么是好的。
They don't get to choose.
他们没有选择。
Be with me.
和我在一起。
Build the new world with me.
和我一起建设新世界。
This is our reason.
这就是我们的理由。
It has been from the beginning,
从一开始就是这样
since you were a little boy
with a bastard's name
当你还是个小男孩的时候
用一个私生子的名字
and I was a little girl
who couldn't count to 20.
那时我还是个小女孩
连20都数不到的人。
We do it together.
我们一起做。
We break the wheel together.
我们一起把轮子弄坏。
You are my queen.
你是我的女王。
Now, and always.
现在，永远。
Where's Jon?
乔恩在哪儿?
He is our prisoner.
他是我们的俘虏。
Sansa: So is lord Tyrion.
珊莎：提利昂大人也是。
They were both to be brought
to this gathering.
他们俩都要被带来
敬这次聚会。
We will decide what we do
with our prisoners.
我们将决定我们要做什么
和我们的囚犯。
This is our city now.
现在这是我们的城市了。
If you look outside the walls
of your city,
如果你往墙外看
你的城市，
you'll find thousands of northmen
who will explain to you
你会发现成千上万的北方人
谁来给你解释
why harming Jon snow
is not in your interest.
为什么要伤害琼恩·雪诺
不符合你的利益。
And you will find thousands
of unsullied who believe that it is.
你会发现成千上万
相信它是清白的人。
Some of you may be quick to forgive.
你们中的一些人可能很快就会原谅。
The ironborn are not.
铁族不是。
I swore to follow Daenerys Targaryen.
我发过誓要追随丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
You swore to follow a tyrant.
你发誓要追随一个暴君。
She freed us from a tyrant.
她把我们从暴君手中解放出来。
Cersei is gone because of her,
瑟曦因她而死
and Jon snow put a knife
in her heart.
琼恩·雪诺放了一把刀
在她心里。
Let the unsullied give him
what he deserves.
让无垢者给他吧
这是他应得的。
Say another word about killing
my brother and I'll cut your throat.
再说一句关于杀戮的话
我哥哥和我会割断你的喉咙。
Friends, please.
朋友,请。
We've been cutting
each other's throats long enough.
我们一直在削减
彼此的喉咙够长。
Torgo nudho.
Am I saying that properly?
Torgo nudho。
我说的对吗？
If it weren't for you and your men,
如果不是你和你的人，
we would've lost the war
with the dead.
我们会输掉这场战争
和死人一起。
This country owes you
a debt it can never repay,
这个国家欠你的
它永远无法偿还的债务，
but let us try.
但让我们试一试。
There is land in the reach.
Good land.
河段有陆地。
良好的土地。
The people that used to live there
are gone.
以前住在那里的人
已经一去不复返了。
Make it your own.
让它成为你自己的。
Start your own house
with the unsullied as your bannermen.
创办自己的房子
让无垢者做你的封臣。
We've had enough war.
我们已经受够了战争。
Thousands of you, thousands of them.
成千上万的你，成千上万的他们。
You know how it ends.
你知道结局。
We need to find a better way.
我们得找个更好的办法。
We do not need payment.
我们不需要付款。
We need justice.
我们需要正义。
Jon snow cannot go free.
琼恩·雪诺不能自由。
It's not for you to decide.
这不是你能决定的。
You are not here to speak!
你不是来说话的！
Everyone has heard enough words
from you.
每个人都听够了
从你。
You're right.
你是对的。
And no one's any better for it.
没人会因此变得更好。
But it's not for you to decide.
但这不是你能决定的。
Jon committed his crime here.
琼恩在这里犯罪。
His fate is for our king to decide.
他的命运要由国王来决定。
Or our queen.
或者我们的女王。
We don't have a king or queen.
我们没有国王或王后。
You're the most powerful people
in Westeros.
你们是最有权力的人
在维斯特洛。
Choose one.
选择一个。
Make your choice, then.
那么，做出你的选择吧。
My lords and ladies...
大人女士们……
I suppose this is the most important
moment of our lives.
我想这是最重要的
这是我们生命中的一刻。
What we decide today will reverberate
through the annals of history.
我们今天的决定将产生深远的影响
通过历史编年史。
I stand before you as one
of the senior lords in the country.
我站在你们面前
这个国家的高级贵族。
A veteran of two wars.
参加过两次战争的老兵。
And I like to think my experience has
led to some small skill in statecraft
我认为我的经历
让我掌握了一些治国之道
- and under...
- Sansa: Uncle?
——在……
叔叔？
Please sit.
请坐。
Well, we have to choose someone.
我们得选个人。
Um... Why just us?
嗯…为什么只有我们？
We represent all the great houses,
but whomever we choose,
我们代表所有伟大的家族，
但无论我们选择谁，
they won't just rule over
lords and ladies.
他们不会只是统治
先生们女士们。
Maybe the decision about
what's best for everyone
也许是关于
什么对每个人都好
should be left to...
应该留给……
Well, everyone.
嗯,每一个人。
Maybe we should give the dogs
a vote as well.
也许我们应该给狗
还有投票。
I'll ask my horse.
我去问问我的马。
I suppose you want the crown.
我猜你想要王冠。
The imp?
小鬼?
Half the people hate me
for serving Daenerys,
一半的人讨厌我
为丹妮莉丝服务，
the other half hate me
for betraying her.
另一半则讨厌我
因为背叛了她。
- Can't think of a worse choice.
- Who, then?
-没有比这更糟的选择了。
-那是谁？
I've had nothing to do but think
these past few weeks.
我除了思考什么也没做
过去的几个星期。
About our bloody history.
关于我们血腥的历史。
About the mistakes we've made.
关于我们所犯的错误。
What unites people?
是什么把人们团结在一起？
Armies?
军队吗?
Gold?
黄金?
Flags?
国旗吗?
Stories.
的故事。
There's nothing in the world
more powerful than a good story.
世界上什么都没有
比一个好故事更有力量。
Nothing can stop it.
没有什么能阻止它。
No enemy can defeat it.
没有敌人能打败它。
And who has a better story...
谁有更好的故事…
Than bran the broken?
比糠碎？
The boy who fell
from a high tower and lived.
那个跌倒的男孩
住在一座高塔上。
He knew he'd never walk again,
so he learned to fly.
他知道他再也不能走路了，
于是他学会了飞行。
He crossed beyond the wall,
a crippled boy,
他越过墙，
一个残废的男孩，
and became the three-eyed raven.
变成了三眼乌鸦。
He is our memory,
他是我们的记忆，
the keeper of all our stories.
我们所有故事的守护者。
The wars, weddings, births,
massacres, famines.
战争，婚礼，出生，
屠杀,饥荒。
Our triumphs,
我们的胜利,
our defeats,
我们的失败,
our past.
我们的过去。
Who better to lead us
into the future?
谁能更好地领导我们
未来？
Bran has no interest in ruling
and he can't father children.
布兰对统治毫无兴趣
他不能做父亲。
Good.
好。
Sons of kings
can be cruel and stupid,
国王之子
残忍又愚蠢，
as you well know.
你很清楚。
His will never torment us.
他永远不会折磨我们。
That is the wheel
our queen wanted to break.
这是轮子
我们的女王想要分手。
From now on, rulers will not be born.
从今以后，不会再有统治者了。
They will be chosen on this spot by
the lords and ladies of Westeros...
他们将在这里被选出
维斯特洛的王公贵妇们……
To serve the realm.
为王国效力。
I know you don't want it.
我知道你不想要。
I know you don't care about power.
我知道你不在乎权力。
But I ask you now,
if we choose you...
但我现在问你，
如果我们选择你…
Will you wear the crown?
你会戴王冠吗？
Will you lead the seven kingdoms
to the best of your abilities
你愿意领导七大王国吗
尽你所能
from this day until your last day?
从今天到最后一天？
Why do you think I came all this way?
不然你觉得我为什么大老远跑来？
To Brandon of house stark...
致史塔克家族的布兰登……
I say aye.
我说是的。
Samwell: Aye.
Samwell明白。
Lord 1: Aye.
主1：是的。
Dornish prince: Aye.
多恩王子：是的。
Yara: Aye.
雅苒:啊。
Lord 2: Aye. Lord 3: Aye.
Lord 2：是的。主3：是的。
I'm not sure I get a vote, but aye.
我不确定我是否有投票权，但是可以。
I love you, little brother.
I always will.
我爱你，小弟弟。
我永远都会。
You'll be a good king.
你会是个好国王。
But tens of thousands of northmen
fell in the great war
而是成千上万的北方人
在大战中阵亡
defending all of Westeros.
保卫整个维斯特洛
And those who survived
have seen too much
那些幸存下来的人
看得太多了
and fought too hard
ever to kneel again.
挣扎得太过艰难
再也不会跪下了。
The north will remain
an independent kingdom,
北方将继续
一个独立的王国，
as it was for thousands of years.
就像几千年来一样。
All hail bran the broken,
所有的冰雹都碎了，
first of his name, king of the andals
and the first men,
他的第一个名字，安达尔人的国王
第一批人，
lord of the six kingdoms
and protector of the realm.
六国之王
也是王国的守护者。
All: All hail bran the broken!
全体：万岁！
Bran: Lord Tyrion...
布兰：提利昂大人……
You will be my hand.
你将是我的手。
No, your grace, I don't want it.
不，陛下，我不想要。
Bran: And I don't want to be king.
布兰：我也不想当国王。
I don't deserve it.
我不配。
I thought I was wise, but I wasn't.
我以为我很聪明，但我并不聪明。
I thought I knew what was right,
but I didn't.
我以为我知道什么是对的，
但我没有。
Choose ser davos.
选择戴佛斯爵士。
Choose anyone else.
选择其他任何人。
- I choose you.
- You cannot.
-我选择你。
-你不能。
Yes, I can.
是的，我能。
- I'm king.
- This man is a criminal.
-我是国王。
-这个人是个罪犯。
- He deserves justice.
- He just got it.
-他应该得到正义。
-他刚拿到
He's made many terrible mistakes.
他犯了许多严重的错误。
He's going to spend
the rest of his life fixing them.
他会花钱的
他的余生都在修理它们。
It is not enough.
这是不够的。
Tyrion: Giving you to the unsullied
would start a war.
提利昂：把你交给无垢者
会引发战争。
Letting you walk free
would start a war.
让你自由行走
会引发战争。
So our new king has chosen
to send you to the night's watch.
所以我们的新国王做出了选择
派你去守夜人。
There's still a night's watch?
还有人值夜吗？
The world will always need a home
for bastards and broken men.
这个世界永远需要一个家
为私生子和破碎的人准备的。
You shall take no wife,
你不可娶妻，
hold no lands,
不要占有土地，
father no children.
父亲没有孩子。
The unsullied wanted your head
of course,
无垢者想要你的头
当然,
but grey worm has accepted
the justice of a life sentence.
但是灰虫已经接受了
无期徒刑的正义。
Sansa and Arya wanted you freed,
珊莎和艾莉亚想放了你
but they understand our new king
needs to make peace.
但他们了解我们的新国王
需要和平。
No one is very happy.
没有人很高兴。
Which means it's a good compromise,
isuppose.
这意味着这是一个很好的妥协，
isuppose。
Was it right?
这样做对吗？
What I did?
我做了什么？
What we did.
我们所做的。
It doesn't feel right.
感觉不对。
Ask me again in 10 years.
十年后再问我一次。
I don't expect
we'll ever see each other again.
我不指望
我们再也不会见面了。
I wouldn't be so sure.
我可不这么肯定。
A few years as hand of the king
当了几年御前首相
would make anyone want to
piss off the edge of the world.
会让人想这么做吗
滚出世界的边缘。
All the men have boarded.
所有的人都上船了。
Good.
好。
We sail for the isle of naath.
我们驶向纳斯岛。
Sansa: I wish
there 'd been another way.
珊莎：我也希望
还有别的办法。
Can you forgive me?
你能原谅我吗？
The north is free, thanks to you.
多亏了你，北方自由了。
But they lost their king.
但是他们失去了他们的国王。
Ned stark's daughter
will speak for them.
奈德·史塔克的女儿
我会为他们说话。
She's the best they could ask for.
她是最好的人选了。
You can come see me, you know,
at castle black.
你可以来找我
在黑城堡。
I can't.
我不能。
You think anyone will dare tell you
women aren't allowed?
你以为有人敢告诉你吗
女性是不允许的？
I'm not going back north.
我不回北方去。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
What's west of Westeros?
维斯特洛的西边是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
No one knows.
没人知道。
It's where all the maps stop.
这是所有地图的终点。
That's where I'm going.
那就是我要去的地方。
You have your needle?
你带针了吗？
Right here.
在这里。
Your grace.
你的恩典。
I'm sorry I wasn't there
when you needed me.
很抱歉我当时不在
当你需要我的时候。
You were exactly where
you were supposed to be.
你当时正好在
你应该是。
That's not... uh...
这不是……嗯…
What's this?
这是什么?
A song of ice and fire.
一首冰与火之歌。
Archmaester ebrose's history
of the wars
埃布罗斯学士的历史
关于战争
following the death of king Robert.
劳勃国王死后
I helped him with the title.
我帮他拿到了头衔。
I suppose I come in
for some heavy criticism.
我想我进来了
因为一些严厉的批评。
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
哦，我可不这么认为。
Oh, he's kind to me.
Never would've guessed.
哦，他对我很好。
我怎么也想不到。
He's not kind?
他不友善？
- He...
- Tyrion: He what?
——他……
他什么？
What does he say about me?
他说我什么了？
I don't believe you're mentioned.
我不相信有人提到你。
- Your grace.
-陛下。
We appear to be missing
a master of whisperers.
我们好像失踪了
耳语大师。
And a master of laws.
还是个法律大师。
- And a master of war.
- Yes, your grace.
-还是个战争大师。
-是的，陛下。
Suitable prospects
will be brought to you
合适的前景
会带给你吗
for an audience in the coming weeks.
为未来几周的观众准备的。
And drogon? Any word?
和drogon吗?什么词吗?
He was last spotted flying east,
toward...
最后有人看见他向东飞，
向……
The farther away, the better.
越远越好。
Perhaps I can find him.
也许我能找到他。
Do carry on with the rest.
请继续做剩下的事。
As you wish, your grace.
如您所愿，陛下。
Ser podrick.
Ser podrick。
We serve at your pleasure,
king bran the broken,
我们为您服务，
国王麦麸破碎，
ruler of the six kingdoms
and protector of the realm.
六国的统治者
也是王国的守护者。
- Long may he reign.
-愿他统治长久。
Long may he reign.
愿他统治长久。
That will improve.
这将会改善。
I'm sure it will.
我相信会的。
Ser bronn of the Blackwater,
黑水河的波隆爵士，
lord of highgarden,
高庭领主，
lord Paramount of the reach
and master of coin,
总督派拉蒙
和钱币的主人，
would you say the crown's debt to you
has been paid?
你会说国王欠你的债吗
付款了吗？
In full, my lord hand.
全部付清，大人。
Good.
好。
Time to start incurring a new one.
是时候开始招致新的了。
We have hungry people to feed.
我们还要养活饥饿的人。
Can we expect some assistance
in this regard?
我们能得到一些帮助吗
在这方面？
Bronn: Indeed we can.
波隆：的确可以。
Lord davos, we have an armada
to rebuild and ports to repair.
戴佛斯大人，我们有舰队
重建和修复港口。
We have.
These projects will begin as soon as
我们有。
这些项目将尽快开始
the master of coin and lord
of lofty titles provides funding.
钱币的主人和领主
高贵的头衔提供了资金。
The master of coin looks foward
to helping the master of ships,
财主向前看
帮助船长，
but first he has to ensure
we're not wasting coin,
但首先他必须确保
我们不是在浪费钱，
or soon there won't be no more coin.
不然很快就没钱了。
"Any more."
“任何更多。”
You master of grammar now too?
你现在也掌握语法了吗？
Grandmaester...
Grandmaester……
It is my theory, based on my years
of work on the casterly rock sewers,
这是我的理论，基于我多年的经验
卡斯特岩沟的工程，
that clean water
leads to a healthier population.
干净的水
使人口更健康。
The archmaester has done
some research on this subject
老学士完了
关于这个问题的一些研究
- and it turns out...
- The strong live and the weak don't.
-结果是…
-强者生存，弱者死亡。
Find the best builders
and set them to the task.
找到最好的建设者
让他们完成任务。
Bronn: Oh, speaking of builders,
all the best brothels burned down.
波隆：哦，说到建筑工人，
所有最好的妓院都被烧毁了。
The master of coin
is willing to fund reconstruction.
钱币大师
愿意资助重建。
Samwell: Uh, the archmaester
is less than enthusiastic
山姆威尔：呃，老学士
不够热情
about the salutary effects
of brothels.
关于有益的影响
的妓院。
Bronn: Well, I imagine
he isn't using them properly.
波隆：嗯，我想
他没有正确地使用它们。
Brienne: I think we can all agree that
ships take precedence over brothels.
布蕾妮：我想我们都同意这一点
轮船比妓院更重要。
Bronn: I think that's
a very presumptuous statement.
波隆：我想那是
这是一个非常冒昧的说法。
Tyrion: I once brought a jackass
and a honeycomb into a brothel.
提利昂：我曾经带过一个蠢驴
把蜂房变成妓院。
Man: The queen in the north!
男：北方的女王！
All: The queen in the north!
全体：北方的女王！
The queen in the north!
北境的女王！